

# **Email** harryprad@gmail.com

#### **Address**

Karthika Niwas, Kuttoor PO, Thiruval la, Pathanamthitta, Kerala

#### Phone

8848571384/8699603191

## Date of birth

Apr 22, 1985

#### **Nationality**

indian

## Skills

Problem-Solving

Teamwork

Leadership

Time Management

Polite dealing with firm decision

**Good Communication Skill** 

Self Propelled

Critical thinking

Interpersonal Skills

Devotion to community

# Languages

English, Hindi, Malayalam, Tamil, (Telugu, Odia and Bengali can understand) Intermediate

## T R Pradeesh Babu

Air Veteran

Joined in the Human Resource department under Administrative Branch of Indian Air Force on 17 June 2002 and rendered 20 years of illustrious service, worked in various fields at premier Flying bases, Liaison Establishments and Command Headquarters. Looking forward to work with zeal where I can grow my knowledge, skills and execute responsibilities entrusted to me by the Organization to the fullest.

## Experience

# Sergeant (Senior Non Commissioned Officer)

Indian Air Force Bangalore/Nashik (Command HQs/Repair Depot)

Dec 2015 - Jun 2022

- Discipline Management, Military Court of Law (conducting Court Martials) and Service Legal Aspects. Holding inquiries and investigations.
- Instrumental in Drafting various HR related Important Policies.
- Documentation and handling of important matters, handling of classified Publications, its safe custody and regular upkeep, maintenance and destruction as per orders.
- Processing of applications for Maintenance Allowance of wives of service personnel.
- Verification of character and antecedent of service personnel from civil police as and when required.

# Corporal (Non commissioned officer)

#### **Indian Air Force**

Delhi, Koraput and Chandigarh (Flying Base, Liaison Establishment and Repair Depot)
Feb 2004 - Nov 2015

- Delhi- Managed Presidents Service Institute where maintained the books of Accounts of Institute, Contract of Shops (30 Shops), prepared Monthly Trial Balance and all relevant Accounting statements.
- Koraput Managed office of HR, data handling (recording, maintenance and updation of service records of service personnel), Presidents Service Institute (Non-Public Funds) and Canteen Stores Department. Gained Vast Experience during handling of Canteen Stores, Purchase, Sales, management of staff of Canteen and its Shop, documentation and preparation of Audit Boards.
- Chandigarh Managed the office of Logistics Support Wing basically dealing with Logistics of the Depot. Dealt with addressing various correspondences of Logistics Department with the rest of the Air Force Bases.

## Trainee

Indian Air Force Belgaum (Karnataka) and Tambaram (Chennai)

Jun 2002 - Feb 2004

Two years rigorous combat training at Belgaum and Tambaram. Studied Clerical duties, drafting correspondences, typing and computer skills. Familiarized with the nature of administration work in Indian Air Force.

### Education

## Service Graduate

**Indian Air Force** New Delhi Jun 2002 - Jun 2022

## Diploma in Industrial Cooperative Management

Institute of Cooperative Management Dehradun

Feb 2022 - May 2022